MD. SABBIR HOSSAIN

Node.js Developer

shr<u>472978@gmail.com</u> • +8801827062978

Portfolio: https://sabbirhossainc.github.io Github: https://github.com/sabbirhossainc LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sabbirhossainbio

Summary

Software developer with 2 years of experience in **React and Node.js**. Also learning **Next.js** and Express.js for providing best performance. Developed various kind of platfrom. Commitment of experience, passion and excellence with proven experiences.

Skills

HTML/CSS • Node.js • React • Express (express.js) • Figma • Tailwindcss • Rest API • Responsive design

Work Experience

Junior Front end Developer

Mar 2021 - Oct 2021 • 7 mos

Dec 2021 - Dec 2021 •

Expert Consortium Ltd. • Internship

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Technologies: React • JavaScript • HTML/CSS

- Updating Promotional ad, displaying on the website.
- Updating content database on website as per requirements.
- · Create new designs as per client requirements.
- Collaborating deployment process with Developers.

Node.js developer Dec 2022 - present

Xebec • Full-time

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Technologies: React • JavaScript • Node.js • HTML/CSS • Astro.js

- · Updating and creating features for websites.
- Create web layout for the required website.
- Create new features as per client requirements.
- · Collaborating deployment process with Developers.

Projects

Gallery App Jan 2022 - Jan 2022 •

1 coworker

Technologies: React • API • Node.js • Tailwindcss • HTML/CSS

Intellectually Disabled And Autistic School

1 coworker

Technologies: React • Material ui • HTML/CSS

Los Angeles mountain Aug 2023 - Aug 2023 •

1 coworker

Technologies: JavaScript • HTML/CSS

Homefi May 2023 - May 2023 •

1 coworker

Technologies: HTML/CSS • JavaScript

Education

Computer Science & Engineering: IT

Jan 2017 - Dec 2020 • 3 yrs 11 mos

Daffodil International University

Dhaka, Bangladesh Grade/GPA: 3.14

Certifications & Awards

UX/UI Design - ICT Division

Full stack Web Development - Bohubrihi

Jan 2021

Languages

English (Full professional proficiency)

Bengali (Native or bilingual proficiency)